<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Green Notebook</title>
    <link>https://jorgeancal.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Green Notebook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 13:44:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jorgeancal.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From Mid Level Java Developer to SRE</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/from-mid-level-java-developer-to-site-reliability-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:15:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/from-mid-level-java-developer-to-site-reliability-engineering/</guid>
      <description>To whom it may concern,
I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to change my way in my career&amp;hellip; Two months ago I started to work as an SRE. Yep SRE. I&amp;rsquo;ve paused my Java Developer career to be an SRE, these are the reasons why I did that.
I think I have to explain one thing&amp;hellip; I started working at Crunch 11 months ago. This was my first job in the UK and believe me my English was awful, I thought I knew how to speak and how to explain things&amp;hellip; until I started to work&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m really glad I had a senior with a lot of patience with me when I was trying to explain myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting with Spring Boot</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/starting-with-spring-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 23:10:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/starting-with-spring-boot/</guid>
      <description>In this post we’re going to have different sections, in the first one, as in all beginner courses, we’re going to define Spring, learn how to create a project with Spring Boot and learn what the meaning of the basic class which Spring gives you when you start a project is.
What’s Spring? If you stop someone on the street and ask them about it, they are going to tell you that Spring is a season of the year, but that’s not the meaning that we want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s going on with Java?</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/what-is-going-on-with-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 23:08:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/what-is-going-on-with-java/</guid>
      <description>The other day there were a few news articles about the new version of Java. I was thinking another one? Really? Like a lot of people in the beginning of their careers, no-one checks the differences between Java versions because they are focused on the projects which they are working on, or maybe it’s just me. But, I had a break between jobs so I decided to update all my knowledge and one thing from my list was this one, so I hope you find this information interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promises in Angular 6</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/promises-in-angular-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/promises-in-angular-6/</guid>
      <description>In this post you will learn about promises in Angular, which I think is a really interesting thing because you really need to know about it when you implement an API in your project and you want to have control of your application and not be crossing your fingers hoping that everything works properly.
Everything I just said happened to me when I started developing in Angular, which is something… I don’t recommend to anyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reasons</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/reasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/reasons/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone. Let’s start again. As you can see, I am back again, I’ve never been really focused on this blog but I think I need to get focused on my things. I have been working a lot the last few months and I realised noone is going to say thanks for working hard. I love to work and I don’t mind spending lots of hours working but, like everyone, I want to hear nice words sometimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Gitlab on Debian 9</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/how-to-install-gitlab-on-debian-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/how-to-install-gitlab-on-debian-9/</guid>
      <description>Let’s go with another installation. I’m not really sure about installing GitLab on my server, but I have been thinking a lot about it. I had installed Git which I like, but I tried one years ago and I like it but I haven’t installed it on my server.
GitLab is a really good tool. You can have it installed on your server and you can create different teams and just developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Jenkins</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/how-to-install-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 22:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/how-to-install-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>In this post I’m going to try to explain what Jenkins is, why we use it, how to install it in Debain and how to use it. Everyone is going to say… oh no! Another boring post about it. I’ll tell them just maybe or maybe not. Find out for yourself.
Firstly, I have to say this post is all my notes about my research about Jenkins, therefore, it could be a bit different than other websites, or just wrong!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary About Oauth2</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/summary-about-oauth2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 23:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/posts/summary-about-oauth2/</guid>
      <description>I know the most of you know what is OAuth2 but some people who is starting in this ‘world’ can be a bit lost in this. So I have tried to prepare a little post which summarizes all the documentation and be a fast read for everyone. Let’s go to start.
What is a OAuth2? OAuth2 is a authentication framework which allows third-party applications to grant access to a HTTP service for websites, mobile application or desktop applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About This Site</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/about-this-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 13:44:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/about-this-site/</guid>
      <description>Hi everybody.
This is the website, I was created a few years ago but my owner tried to update a few things and he lost all my posts because he didn’t do any backups! It’s awful isn’t it?
Now he is trying to fix it by writing more posts but I feel a bit empty and he has promised me lots of things, but the most important is that he is going to create more posts, and it seems like he is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://jorgeancal.com/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 13:44:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jorgeancal.com/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Hi,
My name is Jorge Andreu Calatayud and sorry for my English. I’m a developer. I studied a Bachelor of Science in Business Information Technology, with University of Wales. I worked as Java developer for 5 years in Zaragoza, Spain where I was born and currently I am working in CE-Crunch Ltd.
I like the information technology since I was a baby. Now that I have grow up, I love it because I learn new knowledges every day.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>